Guide to the Lewis Hine Fellowship Photographs Collection, 2003-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Amanda van Scoyoc Photographs Series, 2007-2008, (1 box)
  - When my dad found out that I was pregnant, he told me that he was very angry. He didn't want to talk to me. He insulted me. But I told him that I don't care. I told him that I wouldn't get an abortion because it wasn't his baby. It's my baby and I want it. Kendra (16) 6 months pregnant. (Box 5, Image 07)
  - All I asked him was, "How does he look?" And his response was, "He's perfect, Baby. He's perfect." I thought he was going to come out with 11 fingers. I was just really, really nervous. But when I saw him, he was absolutely beautiful. Melissa (21) and Troy Jr. (2). (Box 5, Image 08)
  - I'm going to raise her right. I don't want her to turn out like me. I want her to be a better person. Melissa (20) and Grace (3 months). (Box 5, Image 09)
  - The only time I was ever locked up I was already pregnant. I was basically in an adult jail and everybody was telling me everything about my case. I could do two years or five years and I was getting scared. I was thinking, "I hope I get out, cause I wouldn't like to have my baby in jail and have my baby go somewhere else." Mercedes (19) and Ameliana (7 months). (Box 5, Image 10)
  - Well, the most fun part of being a mom is that you always have someone there to show love to you and always have someone to give you hugs and kisses. And, the worst part is when they're teething and they just cry and cry and cry all day. And they get into everything. She throws my phone in the toilet. She wants to stick tissue in the toilet and eat it. But she's fun. Monique (20) 5 months pregnant and Treasure (1). (Box 5, Image 11)
  - It will be different for my son because he was born here and I was born in Africa. It's easy to grow up here. He's a citizen. I'm from Somalia and there's a lot of war in Africa. In America there is freedom to learn language and have a good education. Oliya (21), Noordin (4 months,) and 5 of Oliya's nephews. (Box 5, Image 12)
  - First I wasn't ready. First I was like, "I don't want to have her." But my mom was like, "If you take her out then I'm going to take you to the police. I'm going to take you to court cause that's like killing somebody." But then I started thinking that I could be a mother by myself. I could achieve my goals with her. Rosemary (15) and Karolyna (3 weeks). (Box 5, Image 13)
  - I had Naisha when I was 15. I'm only 20. She's four. I'm just about to finish my GED. I like what I'm doing. I want to travel with Naisha. I want to go to Africa and Europe with her. South America, and have this road trip in the States. I don't think I want to go through pregnancy again. I want to adopt orphans. So maybe I'll just adopt orphans after I turn 25 or after I turn 30, and give my love to other kids instead of having more kids. Roxannie (20) and Naisha (4). (Box 5, Image 14)
  - I was 14 when I found out that I was pregnant. At first I didn't want to have it. My mother told me that if she found out I was pregnant she was gonna kick me out of the house. I was like, "No, no, I can't have this baby." But then, you know how when you are pregnant you get curious and you want to know everything? What's growing inside of you? So on the computer I started searching on the word "abortion," and then there were these pictures of abortions and I saw them and I just couldn't abort. Tatiana (16) and Yaitza (2). (Box 5, Image 15)
  - Before, I loved my boyfriend a lot. But now, I don't think of him as my boyfriend. I see him as someone who I want to be responsible for my baby. I want him to be there for her when she needs it. She's my daughter and she's the world to me and I don't want nobody to be ignoring her. Yessenia (15) and Emily (11 months). (Box 5, Image 16)
  - I bought a pregnancy test. He was waiting for me at John's pizza. We ate. We were kind of quiet. I was like, "Don't worry, we're not pregnant. We're just not." And we went back to work and I went straight to the bathroom. At first I didn't really wait and it came back negative. It was a relief for him, you know. Then I looked at it again and it came out positive. I let it sit and wait a little bit, and it came out positive. And of course, I was really happy and he was too, but we were nervous cause we knew our life was going to change. Damaris (8 months pregnant) and her boyfriend. (Box 5, Image 17)
  - I forget to eat sometimes. I'll come to work and be like, "Shoot, I forgot to eat." And my boss will just look at me like, "How do you forget to eat?" But I'm just trying to get them ready and get to work on time. They're cute. They're adorable. But they are a handful. Emily (20), her boyfriend Esli, and sons Evan and Ethan (2 months). (Box 5, Image 18)
  - My baby's father is 21 years old. He supports me a lot in all my decisions. He's good. He buys the baby stuff a lot now so I know he will be a good father. Jennifer (16) 8 months pregnant. (Box 5, Image 19)
  - I think it's basically the same being a young mom or an old mom. Because when you are 30 and you have a baby, you don't know what's going on. When you are 18 --or younger-- you don't know either. The only difference is an older one has been working and has her education. But moms 18 and younger, they don't. Kenny (19) and Angellina (3 months). (Box 5, Image 20)
  - I thought he was going to change. Through the four and a half years that we've been together he had always cheated on me. So he said, "I promise I'll change. I'll never play you cause I love my son, cause I want us to be a happy family." So we moved to NY. We were there for about eight months. The fourth month he started to do the same thing. Sindy (19) and Rey (2). (Box 5, Image 21)
  - What's my baby like? Um, let me see. He just is his own little person. It's really hard to explain. He just has his own little personality. He's just him. Tatiana (18) and Jamari (1 month). (Box 5, Image 22)
  - Being a young mom is really hard. Maybe because you don't know about life, or you are just starting to know about life. You think it'll be really easy, but it's not. Xiomara (17) and Edwin (18 months). (Box 5, Image 23)
  - When you are a child and you get pregnant, that's difficult. I'd love to have another little baby, but not until I finish high school. If I don't graduate then I will wait until I get a GED and a husband, and after that, I will have another one. Zeinab (18) and Ali (3). (Box 5, Image 24)
- Lucy Wilson Photographs Series, 2003-2004, (1 box)
  As a 2003-2004 Lewis Hine Documentary Fellow, Wilson spent six months in 2004 working with the Child Protection Society (CPS), a local child rights advocacy organization. CPS was established in 1952 to promote the rights of children in difficult circumstances in Zimbabwe. Wilson photographed and wrote about CPS’s community-based child care project in the Highfield District, a low-income, high-density suburb of Harare, Zimbabwe’s capital. CPS programming in Highfield includes educational sponsorship, food assistance, youth development, and psychosocial support, as well as community support to child-headed households whose parents have most likely died from HIV/AIDS. As part of the youth development programming, Wilson taught nine children and youth the basics of photography, giving them cameras and black-and-white film. She first asked the youth to write short essays on topics often drawn from the students’ own interests. (The students wrote in English, their second or third language.) They were then encouraged to take photographs based on their writing. Once students developed the images, they selected their best pictures and wrote captions for them (which can be found in the Black and White Prints Subseries). These assignments asked the youth to reflect on the realities of their lives. Wilson's collection from her time in Zimbabwe is entitled The Highfield District of Harare, Zimbabwe.
  Twenty-one color (10) and black-and-white (11) 6.5 x 10" images. Captions for some prints taken from multimedia presentation of the images; others supplied by processing archivist.
  - Color Prints Subseries, 2004
    In some cases brackets indicate supplied titles for uncaptioned prints.
    - [Unidentified woman and young girl beside gate] (Box 6, Image 1)
    - Christina takes a break from cooking lunch for her son, Kundai, and her younger siblings, all of whom she has looked after since her parents died (Box 6, Image 2)
    - Precious, a friend of Christina's comes by nearly every day to visit, sharing chores and meals, and generally supporting Christina (Box 6, Image 3)
    - Three young girls enjoy an afternoon spent playing with jump ropes made from grass (Box 6, Image 4)
    - A barefoot boy runs down his street with a homemade kite (Box 6, Image 5)
    - At camp, Roberta sits and reflects quietly while two boys play as dinnertime approaches (Box 6, Image 6)
    - [Young girl standing by a chair looks to the camera] (Box 6, Image 7)
    - [Man full of joy has he holds infant] (Box 6, Image 8)
    - [Older woman and young boy sit together by a walkway] (Box 6, Image 9)
    - The students test out their new cameras (Box 6, Image 10)
  - Black and White Prints Subseries, 2004
    Made by children in Highfield District, Zimbabwe, with narrated captions. In select captions, the names of children have been changed. In other cases, brackets indicate supplied titles for uncaptioned prints.
    - When I grow up I want to be a pilot. I want to be a pilot so that I can travel all around the world. I know my uncle who is a pilot. I want to pass my primary education and my higher education so that when I grow up I will become a pilot. My uncle can help me so that when I grow up I become a pilot. - Vavariro Kuvenga, 12 (Box 6, Image 1)
    - [Handmade Air Zimbabwe paper airplane] (Box 6, Image 2)
    - This is my form teacher, Mr. Marimo. He is a great teacher. He teaches woodwork and AIDS. He is also a great counselor. He is busy always, and he is a serious man. I like this photo because it is clear and beautiful. - Cecelia Chigwida, 15 (Box 6, Image 3)
    - The one on the left side is my sister Chiedza; the one on the right side is my older sister, Tariro; the one in the middle is my brother, Harold; and the last one in the picture is my father. I took this picture so that I can have a memory when they are not around or alive. I was thinking, is the photo going to be ugly or not, and the people who I was taking the photo of were thinking the same as I was thinking. When I look at it now I think it is the best photo. I like it because almost everyone in our family is in this photo. - Vavariro Kuvenga, 12 (Box 6, Image 4)
    - [Man holding two small children in lap while looking to the camera] (Box 6, Image 5)
    - [At home, preparing to eat a meal] (Box 6, Image 6)
    - [Woman and boy, sitting and enjoying each other's company] (Box 6, Image 7)
    - The people in this photo are my family. I didn't take them for real because they are not around but are faraway. I like this photo because it reminds me of all the people in this photo. - Cecelia Chigwida, 15 (Box 6, Image 8)
    - This is the NSSA house in town. I took this photo because I dreamt I went to NSSA to claim my father's money. When I took this photo I was thinking that I could not photograph the whole building, but I tried my best. I like this photo because I can remember my father through it. - Farai Tango, 14 (Box 6, Image 9)
      The NSSA house is the government building where a Zimbabwean would file to collect a deceased relative's pension. The process of claiming a pension, however, is made difficult by a complicated system that requires multiple forms of identification and documentation. So far, a lack of proper documentation has made it impossible for Farai to receive his father's pension.
    - Here is my mother and her daughter's child. She was ironing my uniforms. I photographed her because I was trying to take photos inside the house. When I look now I will think of my mother's love for me. - Farai Tango, 14 (Box 6, Image 10)
    - [Young boy playing outside] (Box 6, Image 11)